Pedro Antonio Villanueva

Pedro.Villanueva5@gmail.com | (857) 214-1117

A multi-skilled IT Infrastructure Engineer with an in-depth knowledge of architecting, installing, and configuring computing systems. Experienced in providing client-focused IT support and successfully analyzing and resolving IT hardware and software problems in a timely and accurate fashion. Having the ability to maintain a high degree of customer service for all support queries and possessing strong analytical and documentation skills.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Audax Group

October 2016 - Present

IT Infrastructure Engineer October 2016 - Present

- Utilized an IT Service Management framework (e.g., ITIL) to define, deliver and measure services, integrity, reliability, security, and performance of information systems.
- Maintained strategic partnerships with select vendors and Managed Services Providers to support the needs of the business and deliver high quality, cost-effective products, and solutions.
- Hands-on contributor to a project portfolio. Immediate projects included IT Service management system replacement, file server migration to SharePoint Online, desktop imaging re-platforming and business continuity plan testing.
- Ensured client satisfaction through the oversight of end-user services, including Help Desk ticket management, technical support escalations, and meetings and conference room technologies support.
- Establish and maintain regular written and in-person communications with the infrastructure and operations team and business executives regarding relevant IT activities.
- Conduct research on potential technologies in support of business and technology initiatives. Performed beta testing, validation and deployment as required.
- Work with senior management to help lead the IT department's operational and strategic planning.
- Benchmark, analyze, report on, and make recommendation for improvement and growth of the IT infrastructure and business systems.
- Perform ongoing monitoring on all servers (+40) in the operations team environment using PRTG, preventing application outages, maximizing performance, and ensuring 99.9% uptime.
- Audit and troubleshoot Azure services: SAML 2.0 Single-on On, OAuth, Active Directory, Mobile Device Management, Intune, Office 365.
- Audit and troubleshoot network-based services: File and Print services, Active Directory, DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol), DNS (Domain Name Servers), Fortigate Firewalls.
- Lead a team of four IT Operations Engineers responsible for the delivery of technical support to end-users in three domestic offices.

- Worked closely with Executive Technology Manager to support corporate and consumer technologies to executives, executive family members, and executive residences.
- Built training programs and training sessions for technical staff, interns, and prospective employees.
- Contributed to the IT knowledgebase by adding new KB entries and refining entries made by others on the support staff.

Enservio November 2011 - 2016

Team Lead, Desktop Support Team July 2013 – October 2016

Contact Center Phone System Upgrade Project: July 2013 – May 2014

- Determined business requirements with senior management.
- Established phone system following specifications outlined for eight departments.
- Enhanced hardware to increase telephone number diversity by 100% to 400.
- Migrated from in-house phone system to cloud hosted, improving phone system usability from 78% to 99%.

Abandoned Call Rate Improvement: June 2014 – August 2014

- Identified and analyzed a trend in tickets submitted for abandoned calls.
- Determined that the calls were being dropped due to intermittent network connectivity.
- Provided suggestions to facilitate expansion or decommission of the branch office.
- Increased network bandwidth bringing stability to the network infrastructure.
- Decreased the rate of abandoned calls to 1% from 50%.

Sr. Desktop Support Engineer

Email System Migration Project: April 2013 – June 2013

- Updated 330 workstations to meet system requirements for email migration.
- Optimized directory service to meet system requirements of Office 365 Exchange Online.
- Planned, coordinated, and created materials to familiarize employees with a new email platform.

EDUCATION

Gibbs College of Boston – A.S.C.I.S.

Spring 2006 – Spring 2007

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CLOUD TECHNOLOGIES	ADMINISTRATION TOOLS	SECURITY APPLIANCES
MIMECAST M2A	KASEYA VSA	SOPHOS INTERCEPT X ENDPOINT
CISCO MERAKI SWITCHES	PAESSLER PRTG	ZSCALER CLOUDD SECURITY
ZERTO CLOUD DATA MANAGEMENT	MANAGEENGINE ACTIVE DIRECTOR MONITORING	EXABEAM SIEM AND XDR

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Project management, workflow planning, productivity improvement, knowledge management.

Pedro Villanueva

• MA, US

Contact Information

- pnt-vnr-3sa@mail.dice.com
- 8572141117

Work History

Total Work Experience: 10 years

- IT Infrastructure Engineer Audax Group Oct 01, 2016
- Team Lead, Desktop Support Team Enservio Apr 01, 2013

Skills

- engineering 6 years
- framework 5 years
- it infrastructure 5 years
- it service management 5 years
- business continuity 1 years
- firewall 1 years
- fortinet 1 years
- infrastructure 1 years
- it operations 1 years
- kaseya 1 years
- meraki 1 years
- mobile device management 1 years
- productivity improvement 1 years
- siem 1 years
- sophos 1 years
- strategic planning 1 years

- team leadership 3 years
- technical support 3 years
- network 1 years
- network design 1 years

Work Preferences

- Likely to Switch: True
- Willing to Relocate: False
- Work Authorization:
 - o US
- Work Documents:
 - o US Citizen
- Desired Hourly Rate: 85+ (USD)
- Desired Salary: 170,000+ (USD)
- Security Clearance: False
- Third Party: False
- Employment Type:
 - o Full-time

Profile Sources

• Dice:

https://www.dice.com/employer/talent/profile/09bdc519a008eae3f87aeafd5d895bd4